<?xml version="1.0"?>
<BlogDay xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" Date="Wed, 15 Jan 2003">
  <Entries>
    <BlogEntry>
      <Description>&lt;P&gt;So I was doing a very narcissistic thing and looking up my name on google.&amp;nbsp; I found a super early &lt;A href="http://www.forbesfield.com/old-guests.html"&gt;post&lt;/A&gt; to a grafitti board.&amp;nbsp; This dates back to 1994.&amp;nbsp; However, I know that I had a computer up and running on the internet at least in my junior year of high school -- 91-92.&amp;nbsp; It is amazing to think that I've been living with the internet for over 10 years now.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;When I first started working on IE, I jokingly told people that "this whole internet thing would blow over."&amp;nbsp; Well, it did and it didn't.&lt;/P&gt;</Description>
      <BlogEntryNumber>11</BlogEntryNumber>
      <PubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2003 06:02:15 GMT</PubDate>
      <LocalPubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2003 22:02:15</LocalPubDate>
    </BlogEntry>
    <BlogEntry>
      <Description>&lt;P&gt;Again, I'm answering Michael's &lt;A href="http://michaelw.net/Articles/Itsmorethanjustpostingvia.html"&gt;posts&lt;/A&gt; up here -- it is probably better then sending him email or IMing him.&amp;nbsp; If you want to collected related links, there are couple of ways to do it -- one is a system of &lt;A href="http://www.hixie.ch/specs/pingback/pingback"&gt;pingbacks&lt;/A&gt; or &lt;A href="http://www.movabletype.org/docs/mtmanual_trackback.html#reference%20documentation"&gt;trackback&lt;/A&gt; (which I haven't wrapped my head around yet) and the other is to look at your &lt;A href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2002/04/20.html#automatic_linkbacks"&gt;referrer logs&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;[diveintomark.org].&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Apparently, the great thing about standards is that there are so many.&lt;/P&gt;</Description>
      <BlogEntryNumber>10</BlogEntryNumber>
      <PubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2003 05:50:45 GMT</PubDate>
      <LocalPubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2003 21:50:45</LocalPubDate>
    </BlogEntry>
    <BlogEntry>
      <Description>A friend of mine (manager in XBox user test and husband of one of Rachel's fellow residents), Boyd Morrison, was on &lt;A href="http://www.jeopardy.com/mini_sites/archive_header/index.html?/"&gt;Jeopardy!&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;tonight and won.&amp;nbsp; He is going to be on again tomorrow night.&amp;nbsp; He threw a party at another friends house and we watched tonight.</Description>
      <BlogEntryNumber>9</BlogEntryNumber>
      <PubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2003 05:38:43 GMT</PubDate>
      <LocalPubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2003 21:38:43</LocalPubDate>
    </BlogEntry>
  </Entries>
</BlogDay>