<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2003/02/04 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/02/04.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2003/02/04 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2003-2015 Joe Beda CC by-nc-nd 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2003 22:47:16 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/02/04.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>And I&#39;m off</title>
      <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00027.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2003 22:47:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00027.html</guid>
      <description>
&lt;P&gt;I&#39;m off to Boise.  All my stuff is packed up and the guinea pig is packaged up in her carrier.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I probably won&#39;t have time to post again (and work on my software!) until sometime this weekend.  The cable modem is supposed to be installed on Thursday.  We&#39;ll see&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/P&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boise, here I come</title>
      <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00026.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2003 00:56:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00026.html</guid>
      <description>
&lt;P&gt;I meant to write this earlier but I got carried away working on JoeBlogger
&lt;P&gt;I&#39;m moving to Boise for the next 5 months (back in July) to be with my wife.  She is a doctor and her residency takes her to Boise for a year.  She has already been out there since the beginning of July 2002, but it has been really hard being apart.
&lt;P&gt;I&#39;ve worked it out with my management so that I can telecommute.  Everyone at MSFT has been super supportive about this.  I think that the whole thing is just amazing. I&#39;m looking forward to being able to really crank on stuff without all of the interuptions of being at the office.
&lt;P&gt;Now all I have to do is avoid all of the &#34;interuptions&#34; at home

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One more step...</title>
      <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00025.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2003 00:21:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00025.html</guid>
      <description>
&lt;P&gt;This is a test of an entry generated in my tool.  I have to type in raw HTML right now, but everything appears to be working...&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Here is a screen shot of the current UI:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;IMG src=&#34;http://www.eightypercent.net/Stuff/JoeBlogger2.JPG&#34; &gt;
&lt;P&gt;Things yet to do...&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt; Use MSHTML for rich editing.  And switch back and forth in a reasonable way. (Does anyone out there have a simple example I can drop in here?  I&#39;m not looking forward to screwing with all of the interop)
&lt;LI&gt;Automatic upstreaming
&lt;LI&gt;Allow changing of time on an entry
&lt;LI&gt;Deleting and other such management of an entry
&lt;LI&gt;Categories!
&lt;LI&gt;Work on my template to improve the look of my site
&lt;LI&gt;Multiple site management and site configuration.  A lot of stuff is hard coded right now.
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I&#39;ve also decided that storing the entries in an xml file per day is a bad idea.  The timezones will get you.  I store the timestamp on an entry using GMT but the XML file (which is used as input into the UI) is based on local time.  I also use localtime all over the place in the UI.  I&#39;ll probably move to a flat list of entries (one per XML file) at some point and just figure out the local day assignments at runtime.  This will map much better to a real database anyway.&lt;/P&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>