<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2004/10/12 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/10/12.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2004/10/12 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2003-2015 Joe Beda CC by-nc-nd 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2004 08:13:09 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/10/12.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Marathon</title>
      <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00218.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2004 08:13:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00218.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;
        I spent the last weekend in Chicago visiting my parents and my sister&#39;s family and
        her three adorable kids.&amp;#160; (Hi Harper, Ellie and Tate!)
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        We combined this trip with my wife&amp;#160;Rachel&#39;s first marathon!&amp;#160; We took the
        train downtown early on Sunday morning and got there in plenty of time for the start.&amp;#160;
        It was a complete mob scene.&amp;#160; There were 40,000 people signed up to run the marathon.&amp;#160;
        It took Rachel 15 minutes or so to actually get to the start line.&amp;#160; 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I cut across the course and was able to see her run by at the halfway mark.&amp;#160;
        I then took my time walking to the finish line so that I could try to catch a glimpse
        of her on the home stretch.&amp;#160; I missed her there but was able to meet up with
        her in the park outside the finish.&amp;#160; Right after she finished she collapsed on
        me and said that it was the hardest thing she ever did and also the best.&amp;#160; That
        is something coming from someone who finished a medical internship.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I&#39;m so proud of her running it!&amp;#160; Now all she has to do is let her feet heal.&amp;#160;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Interesting stuff:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Everyone is timed with what is called a &#34;champion chip.&#34;&amp;#160; This is a little device
            that you tie on to your shoe that marks when you step on checkpoints along the course.&amp;#160;
            They had 10 of these checkpoints total.&amp;#160; I&#39;m not sure what technology they use,
            but it seems to work pretty well.&amp;#160; There would be no way to get an accurate time
            for 40k people without something like this.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Right after Rachel finished someone in front of her called for a medic.&amp;#160; A woman
            and her father had apparently just finished together when he collapsed on the ground.&amp;#160;
            He was still talking but obviously dizzy and confused.&amp;#160; Rachel introduced herself
            as a doctor and volunteered to help.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;She checked his pulse on his wrist
            and in his neck.&amp;#160; If you have a pulse in your wrist, your blood pressure is at
            least 90.&amp;#160; If it is in your neck it is at least 60.&amp;#160; Since the man had a
            pulse in his neck but not in his wrist he had a blood pressure under 90.&amp;#160; She
            sat with them until the medics arrived and he was wheeled away.&amp;#160; We both hope
            everything is okay!&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            There is a company that tries to take pictures of everyone.&amp;#160; Apparently they
            just shoot away and try to sort it all out later.&amp;#160; Last night when we checked
            the site they had finished going through 22% of the photos they had taken and had
            three pictures of Rachel online.&amp;#160; I can&#39;t imagine dealing with that many pictures!&amp;#160;
            I&#39;m wondering if they have some sort&amp;#160;of OCR system to read the bib numbers off
            the runners.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I took some pictures but I haven&#39;t had a chance to sort through them yet.&amp;#160; Hopefully
        I can put one or two up in the next couple of days.
    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>