<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2004/11/16 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/11/16.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2004/11/16 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2004 18:49:08 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/11/16.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs at Google</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00221.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2004 18:49:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00221.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

    With the advent of our new office, a lot of people have been asking (via email or
    comments on the blog here) about jobs at the Kirkland office.&amp;#160; For a variety
    of reasons, I really can&#39;t do much on the recruiting side.&amp;#160; If I&#39;ve worked with
    you and you don&#39;t work for Microsoft, feel free to drop me a line.&amp;#160; Otherwise,
    your best bet is to send email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jobs@google.com&#34;&gt;jobs@google.com&lt;/a&gt; as
    specified &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/jobs/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; Even though Kirkland
    isn&#39;t listed there, I&#39;m sure you can reference the office in any email you send. I
    wish I could be everybody&#39;s inside line, but I can&#39;t.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Update</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00220.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2004 18:39:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00220.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;
        I&#39;ve been super busy at work for the last few weeks.&amp;#160; We&#39;ve been iterating on
        our stuff and have come up with some cool plans.&amp;#160; Hopefully we can turn those
        into reality and ship them.&amp;#160; I wish I could say more but I really can&#39;t.&amp;#160;
        I think that one of the reasons that Google is so reluctant to speak publicly about
        what they are doing is partly to surprise the competition and partly so that we have
        the freedom to try stuff without committing to deliver it.&amp;#160; There may be some
        stuff that never sees the light of day, but it is better than announcing it and then
        it never seeing the light of day.&amp;#160; I think that this probably makes it easier
        to pull the plug on projects that just aren&#39;t converging.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Besides work, some other things are going on that I think are pretty exciting.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        First, I&#39;ve been helping to port &lt;a href=&#34;http://enblend.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;enblend&lt;/a&gt; to
        build and run natively under Windows.&amp;#160; Enblend is a cool tool to help in the
        blending stage of making digital panoramas.&amp;#160; My (limited) understanding of the
        mechanics is that it converts the images into the frequency domain to come up with
        an optimal blending mask.&amp;#160; Sometime soon I&#39;d like to start delving into the hard
        parts (Math) and get a better understanding of what is going on.&amp;#160; Andrew (the
        guy who wrote enblend) just released version 2.1 out into the wild.&amp;#160; Let us know
        if you have any problems.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Second, I&#39;m going to be missing the Google open house (a rockin&#39; party scheduled for
        Thursday night) so that I can take a trip down to Page, Arizona to shoot slot canyons
        and other various rock formations.&amp;#160; I&#39;m going to be doing a lot of panorama and
        digital mosaic work so look for some cool images soon.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        One interesting photography note: I&#39;ve had one of my large pano&#39;s printed up pretty
        large -- about 40&#34; x 25&#34; (100cm x 64cm, for those of you of the metric persuasion)
        and have it framed and hanging outside my office.&amp;#160; Even at that large size, the
        photo is tack sharp.&amp;#160; It is really a lot of fun to make images that large.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Oh yeah, and Halo 2.
    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>