<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2003/03/31 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/03/31.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2003/03/31 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2003-2015 Joe Beda CC by-nc-nd 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2003 14:16:31 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/03/31.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The latest...</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00071.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2003 14:16:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00071.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the work computer is installing the latest version of longhorn...
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/booksearch/isbnInquiry.asp?isbn=0399149864&amp;itm=1&#34;&gt;Pattern Recognition&lt;/a&gt; by William Gibson.  Short review: Not nearly as good as nueromancer -- wait for the paperback.
&lt;li&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/booksearch/isbnInquiry.asp?isbn=0394555090&amp;itm=1&#34;&gt;Theodore Rex&lt;/a&gt; by Edmund Morris.  This is the followup to &lt;u&gt;The Rise of Theordore Roosevelt&lt;/u&gt;.  After reading both of them, I think that the early life of Roosevelt is more interesting and dynamic.  The detailed description of his years in the whitehouse was something of an anticlimax.
&lt;li&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/booksearch/isbnInquiry.asp?isbn=0374528497&amp;itm=1&#34;&gt;The Metaphsycisal Club&lt;/a&gt; by Louis Menand.  I just started this and it is heavy going.  However, I like it so far.  It isn&#39;t as dynamic (yet) as either of the Roosevent biographies.  I&#39;ll summerize after I finish it.
&lt;li&gt;Music: &lt;a href=&#34;http://music.barnesandnoble.com/search/product.asp?ean=696998641228&#34;&gt;Scarlet&#39;s Walk&lt;/a&gt; by Tori Amos.  This is some of her best stuff since Little Earthquakes.  
&lt;li&gt;Movie: &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.imdb.com/Title?0286499&#34;&gt;Bend It Like Beckham&lt;/a&gt;.  I saw this at the Idaho International Film Festival (Bet you didn&#39;t know that Idaho had a film festival) and I liked it a lot.  I thought it was clever with some hot women in it.  What&#39;s not to like?
&lt;li&gt;Movie: &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.imdb.com/Title?0258068&#34;&gt;The Quiet American&lt;/a&gt;.  This 2002 remake of a 1958 film was very moving.  Starring Michael Caine and Brendan Fraser, it details a love triangle set in pre-US involvement Vietnam in the 50s.  Brendan Fraser is so hit or miss -- remember Monkeybone?
&lt;li&gt;Play: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arbiteronline.com/vnews/display.v/ART/2003/03/20/3e7920b2a19a6&#34;&gt;Icarus&lt;/a&gt; written by Edwin Sanchez and directed by Brian Weaver.  I enjoyed the play a lot -- I haven&#39;t been to a play in a while.  I thought the ending was a little bit of a let down.  It was very open ended.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>