<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2003/11/29 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/11/29.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2003/11/29 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2003 13:13:13 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/11/29.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>More HT thinking</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00157.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2003 13:13:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00157.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;
        Chris -- Thanks for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.simplegeek.com/PermaLink.aspx/c8dae103-c610-4829-bc2d-d9fcb32be084&#34;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt; on
        my theater plans.&amp;#160; I really want to come over and see your setup as long as you
        promise me I won&#39;t drown.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Chris mentioned Paradigms.&amp;#160; I have a set of Paradigm Reference Studio/40 v2 and
        I love them.&amp;#160; I don&#39;t want to take those and repurpose them from my living room
        to my theater so I&#39;m starting over from that respect.&amp;#160; Getting a full HT setup
        with the Studio line is probably more than I want to spend.&amp;#160; However, I&#39;ve been
        reading good things about the Monitor series.&amp;#160; If I can get a good price on them
        from north of the border, I&#39;ll probably do that.&amp;#160; (I was thinking B&amp;amp;W too,
        but I like the sound of my Studio/40s.)
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        With respect to the Infocus ScreenPlay 4800, that projector is just the Infocus X1
        repackaged for the home theater retail channel.&amp;#160; It costs a good $300 more for
        essentially the same projector.&amp;#160; I think that I&#39;m going to up the ante a little
        bit and I now have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.projectorcentral.com/Sanyo-PLV-Z2.htm&#34;&gt;Sanyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.projectorcentral.com/sanyo_plv_z2.htm&#34;&gt;Z2&lt;/a&gt; on
        order.&amp;#160; This is a much higher resolution (720p native) 16:9 LCD projector.&amp;#160;
        It costs more, but I think that the resolution is going to be worth it.&amp;#160; Supposedly
        the latest round of LCD projectors have the contrast ratio that the DLPs are famous
        for.&amp;#160; Beyond this the Z2 has a DVI input.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I couldn&#39;t get the deal on the Yamaha RXV1400 that I thought I could (even though
        I love the idea of a feedback based autocalibration feature) so I&#39;m thinking the Denon
        3803 now.&amp;#160; My current 2ch reciever is a Denon and I&#39;m pretty happy with that.&amp;#160;
        I&#39;ll see if I can get a good deal on the 3803.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Beyond that, I&#39;m going to paint the wall or go with&amp;#160;painted fiber board to begin
        with and then look at buying a screen.&amp;#160; I&#39;m not sure what size I want yet!&amp;#160;
        (6.25ftx3.5ft sounds good to start with.)
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Doing this whole home theater thing is a blast!&amp;#160; There is so much to learn and
        read.&amp;#160; There are tons of good forums and review sites.&amp;#160; The process of just
        figuring out what I&#39;m going to get is a huge undertaking in and of itself.
    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>