<?xml version="1.0"?>
<BlogDay xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" Date="Wed, 7 Apr 2004">
  <Entries>
    <BlogEntry>
      <Title>Great feedback!</Title>
      <Description>
    I'd like to point to and recognize &lt;a href="http://www.kevlindev.com/blog/weblog.php?id=0"&gt;Kevin
    Lindsey&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;for his &lt;a href="http://www.kevlindev.com/blog/comments.php?id=47_0_1_0_C"&gt;great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.kevlindev.com/blog/comments.php?id=42_0_1_0_C"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.kevlindev.com/blog/comments.php?id=41_0_1_0_C"&gt;feedback&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.kevlindev.com/blog/comments.php?id=40_0_1_0_C"&gt;bug&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.kevlindev.com/blog/comments.php?id=39_0_1_0_C"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; on
    graphics in Avalon.&amp;#160; Comments and feedback like this is one of the reasons that
    we gave out the PDC build so early.&amp;#160; Thanks Kevin!</Description>
      <BlogEntryNumber>177</BlogEntryNumber>
      <PubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2004 02:00:56 GMT</PubDate>
      <LocalPubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2004 19:00:56</LocalPubDate>
    </BlogEntry>
    <BlogEntry>
      <Title>Welcome Channel9 visitors</Title>
      <Description>
    &lt;p&gt;
        In case you haven't seen it, part of my interview that I did with &lt;a href="http://scoble.weblogs.com"&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;is
        up at &lt;a href="http://channel9.msdn.com"&gt;Channel9&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; [BTW, big congrats to
        the Channel9 guys.&amp;#160; The site looks great and it survived being slashdotted on
        its first day.&amp;#160; How many dynamic sites do you know can handle a load like that
        so soon after launch?]
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I did a long interview with Scoble and he asked me a lot of questions. It is interesting
        that he the topic of "Is Avalon a way to take over the Web" is the first that they
        put up there.&amp;#160; I'm glad that it is though as this is definately a hot button
        topic.&amp;#160; I'll be sure to keep an eye on the comments on the video and answer any
        questions that you guys have. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        A little background on me: I joined the IE group at Microsoft in the middle of 1997
        right out of college.&amp;#160; I'd interned twice -- once on a forgotten product called
        TeamManager and the second time on the OpenGL inside of Windows.&amp;#160; When working
        on IE, I was responsible for, mostly, the data model for how we stored HTML in memory
        for processing and rendering.&amp;#160; I touched a lot of other code, but my original
        nickname was "Tree Boy" (to &lt;a href="http://www.ericvasilik.com/"&gt;Eric Vasilik's&lt;/a&gt; "Tree
        Man" :)&amp;#160; If you have questions on &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=IMarkupServices"&gt;IMarkupServices&lt;/a&gt;,
        I can probably answer them for you. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        A couple of years ago, I moved over to the then (very newly) formed Avalon Media Integration
        Layer and helped define the early vision of what we were going to do with 2D UI level
        graphics in Longhorn. (The DX team is all over 3D and games!)&amp;#160; At one point all
        we knew that we wanted was CFS, which stood for "Cool Flying Stuff".&amp;#160; We upgraded
        thaet to "Clickable Flying Stuff" and the graphics strategy for Avalon was born.&amp;#160;
        Since then I've been hard at work helping to define and implement a lot of the graphics
        functionality in Longhorn.&amp;#160; Seriously, I think that we are making a huge leap
        ahead for Windows and look forward to helping everyone understand what we are about.&amp;#160;
        I'm also interested in hearing comments, suggestions and bug reports. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
</Description>
      <BlogEntryNumber>176</BlogEntryNumber>
      <PubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2004 23:25:49 GMT</PubDate>
      <LocalPubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2004 16:25:49</LocalPubDate>
    </BlogEntry>
    <BlogEntry>
      <Title>RSS History</Title>
      <Description>
    &lt;p&gt;
        I had a rant here wrt RSS history, but considering the fact that it really doesn't
        matter and it is always best to stay positive, I'll withold comment :).
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Onward and upward with Avalon!
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
    &lt;p&gt;
        Dave Winer has a bug up his but to &lt;a href="http://archive.scripting.com/2004/04/06#When:6:58:43PM"&gt;try
        and claim&lt;/a&gt; that he invented the idea of syndication through XML (embodied via the
        RSS format).&amp;#160; I don't think that anyone will argue that Dave has been syndication's
        biggest evangelist and has driven his fork of the formats forward relentlessly. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I just wish he wasn't such an ass.&amp;#160; RSS (and syndication) like so many things
        in the computer world evolved out of a soup of ideas that stretches way back.&amp;#160;
        Every time Dave &lt;a href="http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rssVersionHistory"&gt;(re)writes
        a history of RSS&lt;/a&gt;, he always lists himself as the original invetor and visionary.&amp;#160;
        The particular history linked to above fails to mention a format that was introduced
        with IE 4 called CDF.&amp;#160; This was &lt;a href="http://www.w3.org/Submission/1997/2/"&gt;submitted
        to the W3C&lt;/a&gt; at least 9 months before the earliest date on Dave's "history."&amp;#160;
        Now, I'd also venture a guess that there are tons of other prior art in the soup that
        CDF came out of.&amp;#160; For someone who rails against the patent system for the way
        it cements credit for ideas that come out of a soup (think Amazon 1-click) he does
        a good job of trying to "patent" RSS. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The really sad part here is that Dave does himself such a disservice.&amp;#160; He has
        a huge bully pulpit that he could use to push his (often) very good ideas.&amp;#160; Instead,
        he spends time trying to rewrite this particular history.&amp;#160; He undercuts his own
        credibility in the process.&amp;#160; Instead of being an elder statesman of the computer
        industry who can cut through the red tape, he sets himself up as a mini Napoleon and
        creates more divisiveness. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I think this quote from &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118715/"&gt;The Big Labowski&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;sums
        up my thoughts on the subject: 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;b&gt;Walter&lt;/b&gt;: Am I wrong?&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;Dude&lt;/b&gt;: No you're not wrong.&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;Walter&lt;/b&gt;: Am I wrong?&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;Dude&lt;/b&gt;: You're not wrong Walter. You're just an asshole.&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;Walter&lt;/b&gt;: All right then. &lt;/blockquote&gt;
--&gt;</Description>
      <BlogEntryNumber>175</BlogEntryNumber>
      <PubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2004 17:29:20 GMT</PubDate>
      <LocalPubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2004 10:29:20</LocalPubDate>
    </BlogEntry>
  </Entries>
</BlogDay>