<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>80%</title>
    <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/07/08.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2003-2015 Joe Beda CC by-nc-nd 4.0</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/07/08.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How the TSA tried to kill me</title>
      <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00194.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2004 15:56:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00194.html</guid>
      <description>

    &lt;p&gt;
        I recently went to New Zealand.&amp;#160; Since it is an outdoorsy type of place I put
        my camelback water bladder/backpack in my big duffle bag and had a great time.&amp;#160;
        Since I&#39;m a responsible hiker, I have a standard emergency kit in my backpack that
        contains things like a compass, foil space blanket, ace bandage, banana powerbars
        (these are so gross I&#39;ll only eat them in an emergency), etc. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Cut to me&amp;#160;going on a hike last Monday and grab my trusty back with the kit already
        put together.&amp;#160; I wanted to put something in my emergency pack and noticed a slip
        of paper from the TSA informing me that they had confiscated my pack of 25 windproof
        matches.&amp;#160; If I had a scanner I would post an image of&amp;#160;the notice.&amp;#160;
        The rule apparently is that knives must go in your checked baggage and matches must
        be in your carryon baggage.&amp;#160; Don&#39;t ask me to explain this.&amp;#160; Also don&#39;t ask
        me to explain why I can&#39;t use my PocketPC to read books during takeoff and landing.&amp;#160;
        These things cannot be explained. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        So, imagine that I had gotten lost in the mountains last Monday and it started to
        get cold.&amp;#160; Normal people would have dispaired and rolled over and died.&amp;#160;
        But not me!&amp;#160; I was a boy scout and was prepared (&#34;Be prepared, its the motto
        of the Boy Scouts!&#34;).&amp;#160; I&#39;d reach in to my emergency kit to get my matches to
        start a fire.&amp;#160; Instead of finding life saving matches I would instead find a
        very official looking notice from the TSA letting me know that I&#39;m screwed. 
    &lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>