<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2003/04/23 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://new.eightypercent.net:81/archive/2003/04/23.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2003/04/23 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2003 11:00:39 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://new.eightypercent.net:81/archive/2003/04/23.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo gallery software</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net:81/post/old/00083.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2003 11:00:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net:81/post/old/00083.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&#39;m going to evolve my blogging software some more over the next couple of weeks.  I want to add the following features:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;True WYSIWYG HTML editing.  I&#39;m still writing HTML directly.  I think that I&#39;m going to steal whatever Chris has in BlogX.
&lt;li&gt;Stories.  I want to be able to easily do one-off pages.
&lt;li&gt;Content macro expansion.  I want to be able to name a page or an entry and have a friendly way to refer to it.  Radio does this (I think) by just looking at words in quotes.  I may do the same.
&lt;li&gt;Photo gallery.  Ideally I&#39;d like to be able to dump a bunch of files in a directory and have it create thumbnails and generate gallery pages.  I&#39;d also want a UI for dealing with this stuff:  Ordering files, adding descriptions, etc.  I&#39;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbase.com&#34;&gt;PBase&lt;/a&gt; for a while now but I think I want a better client side UI.
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now the UI for JoeBlogger is dead simple.  There is no &#34;save&#34; button.  Just a &#34;New Entry&#34; and an &#34;Upload&#34; button.  There is a calendar control for finding entries and a list for all of the entries for that day.  My goal is to keep it that simple as I add these new features.
&lt;p&gt;BTW, I still plan on finishing the stand alone FTP uploader first!
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dante&#39;s View</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net:81/post/old/00082.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2003 10:52:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net:81/post/old/00082.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a panorama from Dante&#39;s View in Death Valley.  We made it up there for this spectacular sunset.  This is a stich of 6 images shot with my 20mm f/2.8 lens on my D60.  It has a horizontal FOV of somewhere around 120 degrees.  Since this is a rectilinear projection, it is equivalent to shooting with a rectilinear 4mm lens.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://static.eightypercent.net/photos/DantesView-Small.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://static.eightypercent.net/photos/DantesView-Thumb.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>