<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2003/11/04 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/11/04.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2003/11/04 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2003-2015 Joe Beda CC by-nc-nd 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2003 20:25:19 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/11/04.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Avalon, XAML and SVG</title>
      <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00153.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2003 20:25:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00153.html</guid>
      <description>

    &lt;p&gt;
        There has been a ton of speculation on SVG and its relationship (or lack thereof)
        to Avalon.&amp;#160; Here is some thoughts on that, collected from various responses I&#39;ve
        made or others have made. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Our rendering model is very much like that of SVG.&amp;#160; We support a hierarchical
            compositing model with transforms that affect items in the hiearchy. 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Our markup isn&#39;t the same mostly because XAML is a direct reflection of the programming
            model.&amp;#160; There is a very solid relationship between the markup and the objects
            and methods. 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Our OM doesn&#39;t match the SVG DOM because we choose to go with an object model that
            more closely matches what we think &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; users expect.&amp;#160; Specifically,
            we tried hard to make sure that our object model provided a certain amount of consistency
            with WinForms (and VB and MFC before it)&amp;#160;and ASP.Net.&amp;#160; Beyond this, our
            object model is strongly typed where much of the SVG DOM is based around strings.&amp;#160; 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            WVG is a term that we are no longer using and isn&#39;t, in my opinion, very useful.&amp;#160;
            We were supposed to have scrubbed this from our documentation, but apparently we missed
            some stuff.&amp;#160; There is no strick subset of Avalon objects and XAML markup that
            stands on its own with respect to vector graphics.&amp;#160; 
            &lt;ul&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;
                    Whereas when using SVG inside of XHTML there is a very&amp;#160;bright line, when using
                    a vector graphic element in a UI authored in XAML, there is no sharp line.&amp;#160; You
                    can put a Rectangle element, for example, in flow with a document without a Canvas
                    element.&amp;#160; To do a similar thing with XHTML/SVG, you would need to wrap all SVG
                    content in an SVG element.&amp;#160; 
                &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;
                    For Avalon, the set of properties and property types is the same between vector graphics
                    elements and other elements.&amp;#160; In this way the background property for a Button
                    is of type Brush -- the same as the fill property for a Rectangle. 
                &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;
                    There are elements that can very easily be seen to belong to both a control subset
                    and a vector graphics subset.&amp;#160; For example, Image makes sense in a UI sense but
                    also in a VG sense.&amp;#160; XHTML and SVG both have image elements.&amp;#160; We avoid this
                    duplicity.&amp;#160; Text is another area where we avoid a large amount of duplication. 
                &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            While we share a rendering model with SVG to a large extent, our support and features
            don&#39;t match up completely.&amp;#160; Some of it is stuff that we haven&#39;t implemented yet
            and others are due to choices that we&#39;ve made because of programming model concerns.&amp;#160;
            I&#39;ll try to put together a guide on this stuff at some point in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I&#39;m sure there are questions around SVG and XAML/Avalon that I haven&#39;t answered here.&amp;#160;
        Post in the comments and I&#39;ll update this post with the latest and greatest.
    &lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I hate Avalon</title>
      <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00152.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2003 20:18:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00152.html</guid>
      <description>

    &lt;p&gt;
        Actually, I&#39;m proud of the work that we are doing on Avalon, but I hate the name.&amp;#160;
        It just sounds lame and dorky to me.&amp;#160; I guess this is what you get when you vote
        on a code name.&amp;#160; Aero and Indigo are much better names.&amp;#160; In fact, the shell
        team has the best code names:&amp;#160;Aero, Jade, Luna, Plex.&amp;#160; I guess it is because
        they have designers who are creative types.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The worst code name I can think of right now was for NT4.&amp;#160; It started out being
        just and update to the shell.&amp;#160; So, it was called the &#34;Shell Update Release&#34; that
        got abbreviated SUR.&amp;#160; They even made T-Shirts that said &#34;We don&#39;t need any stinkin&#39;
        code name.&#34;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Anyone haved examples of other really bad code names for projects?
    &lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>