<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2004/09/27 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/archive/2004/09/27.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2004/09/27 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2004 08:14:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/archive/2004/09/27.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe DNG image format</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/old/00217.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2004 08:14:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/old/00217.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;
        Adobe announced today a new image format for storing raw camera data.&amp;#160; Dubbed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adobe.com/products/dng/main.html&#34;&gt;DNG&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;(for
        Digital Negative) this format is meant to be a common interchange for the fast proliferating
        collection of proprietary raw image formats.&amp;#160; By some estimates there are over
        60 different raw image formats out there.&amp;#160; Because of this, there are really
        only a couple of software vendors that can afford to get into the raw image processing
        game.&amp;#160; It appears that Adobe hopes to level this playing field with this new
        specification. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        To understand the significance of this, it is important that you understand how raw
        image formats work and why they are different.&amp;#160; When most modern cameras (not
        using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foveon.com/X3_tech.html&#34;&gt;Foveon&lt;/a&gt; sensor) advertise
        take a picture, they have a grid of sensors.&amp;#160; These sensors only measure intensity
        but not color.&amp;#160; To capture color data, a color filter (called a Bayer filter)
        is placed over the sensor so that each little sensor only sees one color (typically
        Red, Green and Blue).&amp;#160; That means that the camera only knows one color value
        at each pixel.&amp;#160; This raw data is then processed using a set of complex algorithms
        to produce an image that has all the color information for each pixel.&amp;#160; For each
        pixel in the raw data, these algorithms reconstruct the missing color data by looking
        at the surrounding pixels and &lt;em&gt;guessing&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#160; Because of this guessing, there
        are multiple ways to process this raw data -- and there is the possibility that these
        algorithms and guessing will get better in the future.&amp;#160; Because of this, all
        serious cameras offer a raw mode where the raw (or close to it) sensor data is saved
        in a special format and the complex demosaicing algorithms can be done later on a
        computer. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        So, raw images are fundamentally different from regular images in that they store
        raw sensor data before it has been processed. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The rub comes with the fact that each camera manufacturer has a proprietary raw format
        (or two or three) and some generally crappy software for dealing with it.&amp;#160; Companies
        like Adobe (with the Adobe Camera Raw plugin for photoshop) and Capture One have been
        waging a guerilla war to create products to read all of these formats.&amp;#160; If Adobe
        can succeed in getting camera manufacturers to implement this format in their cameras,
        life for many photographers could become much much easier.&amp;#160; But this isn&#39;t a
        sure thing.&amp;#160; Camera manufacturers are very aware of the business benefits of
        lock in.&amp;#160; They do it with lens mounts and with their software suites.&amp;#160; Canon
        or Nikon may see their proprietary formats as an advantage in the marketplace.&amp;#160;
        Nikon even charges for the software to convert its raw format while Canon and most
        other manufacturers provide it for free. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I haven&#39;t gotten a read from my buddies in Microsoft imaging, but I&#39;m hoping that
        DNG is a huge success.&amp;#160; Assuming that Adobe doesn&#39;t try to assert its own proprietary
        control over the format (Postscript anyone?) it may just let the camera manufacturers
        concentrate on making cameras and leave the software development up to a third party
        marketplace. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        [update: RichB points out that there is also an open source utility for dealing with
        raw camera data called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cybercom.net/~dcoffin/dcraw/&#34;&gt;DCRaw&lt;/a&gt; and
        built by Dave Coffin. Apparently Photoshop (and Capture One?) build on some of Dave&#39;s
        work.]
    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>