<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>80%</title>
    <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/08/13.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2003-2015 Joe Beda CC by-nc-nd 4.0</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/08/13.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Traffic court</title>
      <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00200.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2004 14:09:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00200.html</guid>
      <description>

    &lt;p&gt;
        This morning I spend a couple of hours hanging out in the Redmond courthouse to contest
        a speeding ticket.&amp;#160; I didn&#39;t get my act together enough to file for discovery
        so I couldn&#39;t put together a real defense.&amp;#160; There appear to be two easy ways
        to beat a ticket around here.&amp;#160; First the infraction might not have been filed
        on time.&amp;#160; Second, your trail might not be speedy enough -- two months after the
        infraction, I think.&amp;#160; Neither of these applied to me so I ended up getting a
        deferred finding (a sort of probation). 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        While I probably could have done this via mail, it was enlightening to watch how things
        work.&amp;#160; First, your trial doesn&#39;t get scheduled really.&amp;#160; You are grouped
        with all of the other cases to be covered that morning.&amp;#160; You sit there from the
        beginning of the session until your name comes up.&amp;#160; The judge presiding this
        morning worked it such that the actual lawyers got to go first and the rest of us
        schmoes representing ourselves go after that.&amp;#160; It was interesting to see how
        much time it really took the lawyers to beat a case.&amp;#160; It mostly was about finding
        a loophole and arguing it.&amp;#160; The judge has some discretion as to how to interpret
        things but most of it is cut and dried.&amp;#160; 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The thing that really surprised me was that by the time my case came up there were
        no lawyers in the room.&amp;#160; This included the prosecutor.&amp;#160; I think it really
        sucks that you can be tried for an infraction without a prosecuting attorney even
        present.&amp;#160; To me it is a slap in the face that the state wants to extort money
        out of me (via the traffic ticket) without even bothering to have somebody there to
        personally do the extorting.&amp;#160; At least the mafia comes and collects in person.&amp;#160;
        Apparently this has been fought over and gone to the Supreme Bourt (at least that
        is what the judge said)&amp;#160;but I don&#39;t have the time to really dig in to it. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        In any case, I would urge everyone to contest a ticket just once to see how it all
        works.&amp;#160; Or just show up in Redmond courthouse courtroom two any morning and sit
        and watch. 
    &lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEC to examine Playboy for boobs</title>
      <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00199.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2004 14:09:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00199.html</guid>
      <description>

    Get your mind out of the gutter.&amp;#160; The Register comes up with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2004/08/13/larry_sergey_playboy/&#34;&gt;best
    headlines&lt;/a&gt;.

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>