<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2004/11/27 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/11/27.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2004/11/27 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2004 09:03:57 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/11/27.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos from the Arizona Desert</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00223.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2004 09:03:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00223.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;
        Last weekend I spent some time down near Page, AZ photographing some beautiful southwest
        scenery.&amp;#160; Since I don&#39;t have the time or experience to plan something like this
        myself, I went with a group of people led by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.f-8andbethere.com/about.htm&#34;&gt;Steve
        Kossack&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.f-8andbethere.com/&#34;&gt;f-8 and be there&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;
        Steve takes people out on photography workshops to places that he knows very well.&amp;#160;
        It is&amp;#160;amazing what a difference an experienced leader can make to an expedition.&amp;#160;
        I had a great time and got some amazing images from the trip. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        My flight to Phoenix on Thursday got in around 1:30 pm.&amp;#160; Steve and some of the
        other participants picked me up at the airport baggage claim.&amp;#160; We were then immediately
        off on a pretty long drive up to Page.&amp;#160; Page is right on the border between Arizona
        and Utah.&amp;#160; It&#39;s on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.powellguide.com/lakepowell/lakepowellmap.html&#34;&gt;Lake
        Powell&lt;/a&gt;, a huge serpentine lake made by the Glen Canyon Dam.&amp;#160; The Glen Canyon
        dam is on the Colorado upstream from the Grand Canyon. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Once at page, we checked in to a hotel and started our 3 days of intense field photography.&amp;#160;
        A typical day would be getting up early enough so that we could be at a good spot
        for sunrise.&amp;#160; Up in the high desert this was pretty cold this time of year.&amp;#160;
        Lows at night were somewhere around 35-40 degrees F.&amp;#160; We would then photograph
        the sunrise.&amp;#160; After that we would spend the day in locations that work well with
        overhead light.&amp;#160; For this trip we photographed both upper and lower Antelope
        Canyons.&amp;#160; These are amazing slot canyons that really have to be seen to be believed.&amp;#160;
        As the day wears on we would travel to another amazing location for a sunset shoot. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Besides the wonderful landscapes, the other people on a trip like this make it a very
        enriching experience.&amp;#160; It is refreshing to me to be out with people who enjoy
        photography so much.&amp;#160; It takes a certain type of person to get up at 4:30am in
        the cold so that you can travel two hours to be in time for the morning light.&amp;#160;
        One part of the workshop that I particularly enjoy is the print discussion.&amp;#160;
        Steve encourages everyone to bring some prints of their work.&amp;#160; Then, after living
        with each other for a couple of days, we get together to admire and discuss each others&#39;
        work.&amp;#160; Steve also brings some of his best work for us to look at. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        If you are interested in an experience like this and have&amp;#160;a passion for photography,
        give Steve a call.&amp;#160; His upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.f-8andbethere.com/workshops/rafting05.htm&#34;&gt;Grand
        Canyon rafting trip&lt;/a&gt; looks like a trip of a lifetime.&amp;#160; I won&#39;t be able to
        make this one, but it looks like he has a couple of spots left. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        As for the images that I got -- here is a start: 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;Horseshoe Bend at dawn&#34; hspace=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://www.eightypercent.net/photos/HSB-thumb.jpg&#34; align=&#34;baseline&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt; 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        This is famous Horseshoe Bend on the Colorado river.&amp;#160; The river&amp;#160;carves a
        perfect circle as seen from&amp;#160;the cliff overlooking the canyon.&amp;#160; This was
        our first sunrise of the trip.&amp;#160; I&#39;m always a little rusty when starting out on
        something like this, but I&#39;m happy with this result.&amp;#160; The mountains in back (catching
        the sun first) are called the Vermillion Cliffs. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Technical details: 20 images stitched together (3x7) shot from my Canon 20D with the
        24-70mm f/2.8L at 34mm.&amp;#160; Exposure was 1/25th second at f/11 and ISO 200.&amp;#160;
        I haven&#39;t done the full stitch yet (this is a small version) and so I don&#39;t know the
        final resolution. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Look for more images in the coming weeks as&amp;#160;I sort through the boatload of data
        I captured.&amp;#160; As a point of reference, I ended up with ~14GB of raw data from
        this trip.&amp;#160; I&#39;m going to run out of disk space! 
    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>