<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2004/06/18 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/06/18.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2004/06/18 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2003-2015 Joe Beda CC by-nc-nd 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2004 20:00:58 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/06/18.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Defending the Rich Client</title>
      <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00190.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2004 20:00:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00190.html</guid>
      <description>

    &lt;p&gt;
        It probably goes without saying, but these comments are my own and don&#39;t represent
        any official position by Microsoft. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        There has been an interesting discussion &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblog.infoworld.com/udell/2004/06/09.html#a1019&#34;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; by
        Jon Udell and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/APIWar.html&#34;&gt;continued&lt;/a&gt; by
        Joel Spolsky (&lt;a href=&#34;http://developers.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=04/06/16/209202&amp;amp;tid=&#34;&gt;discussed&lt;/a&gt; on
        Slashdot). In both of their articles/postings they have referenced the &lt;a href=&#34;http://channel9.msdn.com/ShowPost.aspx?PostID=948&#34;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; that
        I gave quite a while back for &lt;a href=&#34;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2004/06/18.html#a7784http://scoble.weblogs.com/&#34;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt; for
        Channel 9. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.25hoursaday.com/weblog/PermaLink.aspx?guid=49250729-fd67-4dd1-a960-2a6a8f55d9cb&#34;&gt;Dare&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.longhornblogs.com/robert/archive/2004/06/18/3731.aspx&#34;&gt;Robert
        McLaws&lt;/a&gt; have also responded.&amp;#160; My buddy from high school, Vince Anichini, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.articulatebabble.org/archives/2004/06/17T004246.php&#34;&gt;wants
        in&lt;/a&gt; on the action too. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Go ahead and read them if you haven&#39;t already and then come back. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Here is my summary so that Jon, Joel and everyone else can make sure that I&#39;m reading
        them right. First, Jon is asking why anyone (and the &#34;enterprise&#34; specifically) would
        want to write a rich client (probably for any platform) above and beyond a web application.
        Joel takes this and runs with it -- saying essentially that the rich client is dead
        and that the Windows API is dying with a whimper. He also says that there are two
        camps of developers inside of Windows: those that want to keep on the same track and
        those who are for all the new technologies. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;IE history 
    &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Being on the Windows team, and Avalon specifically, my job is to help write a product
        that is compelling enough to overcome the very valid concerns that these guys have.
        I started out on the IE team (now you know where at least a little bit of the IE team
        went, Joel) back in 1997 -- toward the tail end of IE4 development. I firmly believe
        that we had the better product starting with IE4 and we really turned up the heat
        with IE5. IE was, in a lot of ways, a rear guard action against Netscape. Netscape
        was trying to replace the Windows API with a cross platform &#34;Netscape&#34; API. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        IE was, buy many metrics, very successful. First, we gained significant adoption.
        I personally think that this was mostly due to a superior product. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Second, we also, by making the browser market a 2 horse race, drove baseline interoperability
        in the web space. Where would the world be without IE? Do you think that we would
        have an interoperable browser space now? Based on pure psychic reasoning, my guess
        is that without the healthy competition from MS, Netscape would have owned the client
        space completely. At this point I don&#39;t think that &lt;i&gt;anyone&lt;/i&gt; owns the web client
        platform. Despite IE&#39;s market share, the network addressable platform pieces that
        anyone uses are largely restricted to the W3C blessed parts. So, taking a look at
        the IE4 and IE5 timeframe, in some ways you can thank Microsoft for enabling a mostly
        standards based web by making the browser a two horse race. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Where IE wasn&#39;t successful was in bringing the Web model in as a fundamental part
        of the Windows API. Sure, you had the reusable browser control and the Trident (mshtml.dll)
        engine. But you were either writing a web-like application (HTAs included) or you
        were writing a Win32 application. There were certain things that were easy to do with
        traditional Win32 that you couldn&#39;t do with IE and things that you could do easily
        with IE that you couldn&#39;t do with Win32. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;The best of windows and the best of the web 
    &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Avalon, and Longhorn in general, is our attempt to reenergize the rich client at Microsoft.
        Is it, as Joel says, too late? I don&#39;t think so. I think that the combination of features
        we are putting together will be compelling enough to start turning the tide. Are we
        ever going to see a world where the web is history and all development is focused
        on writing Longhorn applications? Of course not. Longhorn is a long term investment
        to start laying the ground work for a rich client that takes advantage of the web
        in a way that we have never been able to before. This is what we mean when we say
        that we want to make Avalon the best of Windows and the best of the Web. We want to
        take some of the advantages of the web and build them in to the windows API. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Why do people write web based client/server apps over writing rich client apps for
        Windows? 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Frictionless deployment story 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Cross platform interoperability 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            More fun to code -- you can set up your own API system and abstract HTML to a large
            extent 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Built in network/server awareness 
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        You put all of these together and you have a pretty darn compelling story for many
        scenarios. How can the Windows client compete with this? The key is to take the good
        things of the web that we can (1, 3 and 4) and combine that with all of the goodness
        from having stuff run on the client. Don&#39;t get me wrong -- I still believe in the
        web as a way to interoperate and exchange content and as a lowest common denominator
        for UI interaction. But we can do so much better than HTML with the horsepower that
        is sitting on our desk when it makes sense to do so. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        For example, Joel says that he can &#34;install&#34; GMail by hitting Ctrl-D, gmail, Ctrl-Enter.
        My understanding (and I haven&#39;t had time to really play with GMail yet) is that Google
        has written browser specific code to enhance the user experience. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        With Avalon you should be able to implement a GMail like application that takes advantage
        of the rich client in some very significant ways: 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;b&gt;Rich user experience&lt;/b&gt;.&amp;#160; No page refreshes on simple actions.&amp;#160; Smooth
            animation and graphical composition.&amp;#160; The ability to do rich real time data visualization. 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;b&gt;Local Storage&lt;/b&gt;. Cache the mail data locally for faster access and more integration
            with other desktop services.&amp;#160; You could also support reading and responding to
            mail while offline. 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;b&gt;Easy network connectivity&lt;/b&gt;.&amp;#160; Using web services, the ability to use widely
            interoperable protocols to talk with a server. 
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Will this be possible in Longhorn? YES. This is the direction that we want to go and
        what I mean when I say &#34;network connected rich client applications.&#34; We aren&#39;t replacing
        the web or the web paradigm. We are instead providing the platform so that it is easy
        -- and &lt;i style=&#34;mso-bidi-font-style: normal&#34;&gt;worthwhile&lt;/i&gt; -- for developers to
        differentiate when their applications are running on Windows. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;But what about the enterprise? 
    &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Now, to get to some specific points brought up in the articles. Jon brings up some
        good points around the enterprise space. I can only say that we are working hard to
        build a package of features on the client that will either make enterprise developers
        willing to standardize on Longhorn or take the extra cost to provide a rich client
        solution in addition to a web based solution. There are some applications where this
        will never make sense. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        However, there are a set of applications that are currently being implemented on against
        today&#39;s web clients that could be vastly improved by rich client capabilities. I can
        definitely see a need for a rich expense reporting application with a good offline
        mode and rich display and reporting. Anything that involves charting or graphing can
        also be enhanced by using some rich client technologies. I use Outlook every day to
        do email. There is a web solution for Exchange called &#34;Outlook Web Access&#34; (OWA) that
        uses DHTML and all of the other web goodies to provide as good an experience as possible
        through the web client. While I think that OWA is great and I&#39;m a huge fan of what
        those guys are doing, I&#39;d still much rather use the real Outlook. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        With Avalon we are hoping to make it vastly easier to write rich data connected applications
        like Outlook. However, we don&#39;t want stop there. We also want developers to be able
        to get the best of the web. These applications can run in the browser for the browser
        experience or can be &#34;one click&#34; installed and run on the desktop.&amp;#160; Even when
        they are &#34;installed&#34; they can be managed from the server and be kept up to date as
        easily as copying a new version on to the server. Think of how many enterprise LOB
        apps could benefit from that? Expense reporting (with offline mode), &#34;Digital Dashboard&#34;
        data aggregation and visualization, integrated content creation, new network connected
        collaboration applications and more.&amp;#160; 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Backward compatibility 
    &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Now, talking to some of Joel&#39;s points: He says that we have fundamentally changed
        our view of backward compatibility. I totally disagree. As one Slashdot poster &lt;a href=&#34;http://developers.slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=111332&amp;amp;cid=9446923&#34;&gt;put
        it&lt;/a&gt;: &#34;Joel confuses binary compatibility with API compatibility.&#34; From the end
        users point of view we are still completely committed to making apps that run on Windows
        continue to run on Windows. At the PDC, Jim Allchin showed off &lt;s&gt;Lotus 123&lt;/s&gt; Visicalc
        running on Longhorn. The developer experience, however, will have a gap -- it is necessary
        as part of the transition to managed code. He states that VB.Net not being source
        compatible with VB6 is a first. I would argue that the switch from 16 bit to 32 bit
        is very similar to the switch from unmanaged code to managed code. Old apps will continue
        to run and new apps are written to the new technology. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        In Avalon we are working very hard to provide rich ways for application developers
        to tie their old code in with new code that takes advantage of our new technologies.
        You can host a Win32 hwnd -- WinForms based or not -- in with Avalon content. You
        can also host Avalon content in a Win32 hwnd. You can nest these completely. While
        it is true that you have to write new code to get the new features -- and that the
        new code is part of a completely new framework -- we don&#39;t want to force application
        developers to rewrite everything to start using our stuff. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Above and beyond what Avalon has been doing, the C++ team has heard what the community
        has been saying and is doing some great work in Whidbey to make the managed version
        of C++ better than ever.&amp;#160; It will be the best solution for those who have the
        C++ code and skills and want to start taking advantage of the the CLR. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;What&#39;s a $300B (market cap) company to do? 
    &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The real question is: What are we to do? Without arguing about the fine points, we
        are stuck with a choice. We can either continue adding doodad on top of doodad to
        Win32 (and maintain backward compat from an API and binary perspective) or we can
        try and make a fresh start with WinFX and set ourselves up for the future. Look at
        the timelines: Windows 1.0 with the start of Win16 came out in 1985. Windows 95, with
        the mainstream advent of Win32 came out in 1995. It is now 2004. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Now is the time for Microsoft to either watch the Windows rich client sail in to the
        sunset or to do its best to reinvigorate it. The only way to make this happen is to
        go &#34;all-in&#34; and think big. We want to empower developers by making a much richer,
        network connected and modern API for programming on windows. WinFX is all about taking
        what we&#39;ve learned over the last 20 years and creating a solid platform for the next
        20 years. We will provide the right API, backward compat for old applications and
        a great bridge between the two for developers. If we really want developers to write
        code that only runs on windows, we have to provide features and enticements that they
        can&#39;t get anywhere else. While I don&#39;t think that it is too late, I do think that
        we have our work cut out for us. 
    &lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>