<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2003/02/24 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://new.eightypercent.net:81/archive/2003/02/24.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2003/02/24 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2003 16:05:02 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://new.eightypercent.net:81/archive/2003/02/24.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>New tripod</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net:81/post/old/00049.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2003 16:05:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net:81/post/old/00049.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Ordered one of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bogenphoto.com/product/templates/templates.php3?sectionid=274&amp;itemid=773&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; bad boys today.  I can&#39;t wait.  I&#39;m also going to order one of &lt;a href=&#34;http://acratech.net/prod01.htm&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; pretty soon too.
&lt;P&gt;My old tripod had a bent leg and was super heavy.  With this combo I&#39;ll be set to carry the tripod on longer hikes.  Things should start warming up soon and I can start exploring the environs around Boise.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WWCDD?</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net:81/post/old/00048.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2003 07:39:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net:81/post/old/00048.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://michaelw.net&#34;&gt;Michael Winser&lt;/a&gt; suggested that I should think about taking the same approach that citydesk uses.  They do two things differently than Radio:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They use a CRC instead of a byte for byte comparison.  Apparently they use this instead of filetimes altogether.  I could compute the CRC (or do the comparison with the file on disk too, I guess) by wrapping the stream that the transform is writing to and doing the CRC/comparison on the fly
&lt;li&gt;They also post a list of files and CRCs as an xml file on the server. This makes it easier to synchronize files across machines
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely want to enable the cross machine case, and file times do seem a little fragile to me.  This is something I&#39;ll have to think about a little more.
&lt;p&gt;Two way synchronization is really hard though?  What happens if the same file changes on both the client and the server?  How do you handle deleting a file?  (Do you care about deleting a file?)
&lt;p&gt;Another problem comes up when you have multi-party authoring and syncing and that is with respect to item numbers.  Right now I have an item number count that I store in a config file and update every time I create a new entry (it is currently at 49).  &lt;a href=&#34;http://simplegeek.com&#34;&gt;ChrisAn&lt;/a&gt; solves this problem with a good old fashion GUID (I have a bunch cheap if you need them ;)  I might be able to switch over without killing my RSS feed and perma links if I just treat the item ID as a string.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>