<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2004/04/12 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/04/12.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2004/04/12 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2003-2015 Joe Beda CC by-nc-nd 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2004 09:30:52 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2004/04/12.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Stress duty</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00180.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2004 09:30:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00180.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;
        Here in Windows (and in other groups around the company) we have a system that is
        generally called stress.&amp;#160; Different groups have different implementations, but
        the idea is always the same.&amp;#160; You develop a test suite that hammers you system
        and&amp;#160;then have everyone install it and run it overnight.&amp;#160; The idea is that
        this way we can catch those hard to repro issues that only our customers see. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        When you get one of these errors, what do you do with it?&amp;#160; Generally there is
        a team of people who have the thankless job of coming in early, finding all the machines
        that have broken in to the debugger, logging the failures in a database and having
        the system send mail to various people to investigate.&amp;#160; The actual debugging
        is done via the NT command line debugger (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/whdc/ddk/debugging/default.mspx&#34;&gt;cdb&lt;/a&gt;)
        redirected over the network via the remote.exe utility.&amp;#160; It is up to this team
        to figure out which issues have already been caught and fixed (but perhaps aren&#39;t
        in the build yet) and what issues are new and need to be investigated.&amp;#160; These
        guys cover a lot of code so the generally don&#39;t have the knowledge to figure out what
        developer should be looking at any particular problem.&amp;#160; That falls to the rotating
        list of people who are on &#34;stress duty.&#34;&amp;#160; The shell team calls it &#34;dev of the
        day.&#34;&amp;#160; We&#39;ve learned by hard experience that if you send these types of things
        to a big mailing list, they either get ignored or the same sorry glutton for punishment
        picks up all of the issues. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I happen to be on stress duty this week.&amp;#160; My job is to handle, in as expedient
        a fashion as possible, any incoming issues.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;I&amp;#160;have to do my best to
        exercise&amp;#160;my debugging skills and try to figure out what is going on.&amp;#160; BTW, &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblogs.asp.net/oldnewthing/&#34;&gt;Raymond
        Chen&lt;/a&gt; is one of the undisputed masters of the cdb kung-fu.&amp;#160; If I can figure
        out what is going on myself, I can file a bug on the issue and let the person whose
        machine I&#39;m debugging reclaim their machine.&amp;#160; If the problem is in code that
        I don&#39;t know well it is my job to reassign the issue to someone who does know the
        code well.&amp;#160; 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Beyond handling incoming stress breaks in the morning, I also have to be responsive
        to all sorts of other issues that might get dropped on the floor.&amp;#160; This includes
        other random crashes people might have during the day along with helping out to resolve
        any build breaks.&amp;#160; (We try super hard to make sure that build breaks don&#39;t happen,
        but with something the size of Windows it still sometimes happens.) 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Do other companies have systems like this set up?&amp;#160; I&#39;d be interested to hear
        what works for you. 
    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managed/Unmanaged lines</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00179.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2004 09:20:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00179.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;
        Over on Channel9, there was an &lt;a href=&#34;http://channel9.msdn.com/ShowPost.aspx?PostID=1653&#34;&gt;interesting
        question&lt;/a&gt; about the history of how my team in Avalon decide to split our component
        between managed and unmanaged code.
    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>