<?xml version="1.0"?>
<BlogDay xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" Date="Sat, 3 May 2003">
  <Entries>
    <BlogEntry>
      <Title>WYSIWYG in JoeBlogger</Title>
      <Description>
    &lt;p&gt;
        I was finally able to find time to put true WYSIWYG HTML editing into JoeBlogger.
        Here is a current screenshot:&lt;br /&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://static.eightypercent.net/stuff/JoeBlogger3.JPG" /&gt; 
        &lt;br /&gt;
        Notice that there is no save button.&amp;#160; Just start a new entry and hit Upload.&amp;#160;
        It FTPs everything that has changed to your site on a background thread. If you don't
        hit upload, it will automatically save your unpublished entry.&amp;#160; I really like
        the UI model with no explicit "save" functionality.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I stole the HTML editing control code (which is really a wrapper around IE's rendering
        engine: Trident) from &lt;a href="http://www.simplegeek.com"&gt;ChrisAn's&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.gotdotnet.com/Community/Workspaces/Workspace.aspx?id=ddc98753-6559-489b-a533-57034790a93a"&gt;BlogX&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;
        He stole it from Nikhil Kothari&amp;#160;who wrote it originally&amp;#160;&lt;a href="http://www.asp.net"&gt;ASP.NET&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.asp.net/webmatrix/default.aspx?tabindex=4&amp;amp;tabid=46"&gt;WebMatrix&lt;/a&gt; project.&amp;#160;
        The HTML -&amp;gt; XHTML conversion code was written by Andrew Lin. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Note that JoeBlogger is a very different project than BlogX.&amp;#160; BlogX is a client/server
        solution that has the canonical data store on the server.&amp;#160; It requires a ASP.Net
        server to run the server side part (Actually, you could probably write a different
        server that expose the same API, but you get the idea).&amp;#160; JoeBlogger is a client
        side only solution that doesn't have &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; server side code at all.&amp;#160; All
        of the pages are generated on the client and uploaded to the server.&amp;#160; As long
        as you have FTP access to your web server (and almost everyone does) you are set. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        If you are interested in getting&amp;#160;a look at the JoeBlogger source, let me know
        and I can give you an early drop of the source.&amp;#160; I'll probably add some more
        features (and a decent setup) and then release it. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
</Description>
      <BlogEntryNumber>88</BlogEntryNumber>
      <PubDate>Sat, 03 May 2003 18:08:10 GMT</PubDate>
      <LocalPubDate>Sat, 03 May 2003 12:08:10</LocalPubDate>
    </BlogEntry>
    <BlogEntry>
      <Title>New ISP?</Title>
      <Description>
    &lt;p&gt;
        I'd like to switch to a new ISP. Here is what I'm looking for: 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Reasonable rates. I'm thinking ~$20/month tops. 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            ASP.Net hosting 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            500Mb to 1Gb of space. I'd like to be able to put a lot of pictures up there. 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            No frills support 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Reasonable access to log files. 
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        It seems like there are a ton of LAMP shops out there offering a deal like this but
        I can't find anything that will host ASP.Net. Anyone know anything I don't? Do i have
        to get a bunch of friends together and colocate a box? Most places look like they
        really rip you on extra storage space. If I can't find anything good then I may drop
        the ASP.Net requirement and do most everything client side and FTP static pages up
        like I'm doing now. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Email me at 'Eightypercent at Bedafamily.com' if you have any ideas for me. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
</Description>
      <BlogEntryNumber>87</BlogEntryNumber>
      <PubDate>Sat, 03 May 2003 15:52:46 GMT</PubDate>
      <LocalPubDate>Sat, 03 May 2003 09:52:46</LocalPubDate>
    </BlogEntry>
  </Entries>
</BlogDay>