<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2003/03/03 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/03/03.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2003/03/03 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2003 10:04:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://new.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/03/03.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>More FTP stuff</title>
      <link>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00056.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2003 10:04:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://new.eightypercent.net/post/old/00056.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.simplegeek.com/permalink.aspx/55cdfe57-82bf-47aa-9beb-5dc06d966724&#34;&gt;Bitch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.simplegeek.com/permalink.aspx/063d639b-10c7-4826-9f5f-0b6c026a9268&#34;&gt;bitch&lt;/a&gt;, bitch.  Okay, Chris, what &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; you want in the FTP upstreamer?  I don&#39;t think that Radio&#39;s upstreamer deletes either.  Here is what I can do easily:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CD to a directory.  Throw if the dir isn&#39;t there.
&lt;li&gt;[done] Ensure a directory.  Try my best to make sure that a directory (and the path up to it) exists.
&lt;li&gt;Delete a directory.  The server will probably return an error if there are files in it.  I will throw.
&lt;li&gt;Get the current directory.
&lt;li&gt;Move up a direcotry.
&lt;li&gt;[done] Upload a file into the current directory.
&lt;li&gt;Download a file in the current directory and return a stream.  It would be easiest to buffer the entire file in memory.
&lt;li&gt;Delete a file in the current directory.
&lt;li&gt;[done] Return a text string with the current directory listing.
&lt;li&gt;Call SYST and return whatever the system gives us.  This might help detect the type of system on the other end.
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that isn&#39;t easy and that will probably take quite a while to get right is parsing the output of the directory listing.  I don&#39;t have a bunch of servers to test this against to make sure it will work.
&lt;p&gt;As for the upstreamer itself, I&#39;d rather have it not try and sync the stuff on the server (and hence delete stuff) because I&#39;d be afraid of loosing data.  For instance, I upstream into the root of my site and I have all sorts of subdirs off of that.  I&#39;m setting up a weblog for Rachel on eightypercent.net and her root will be a subdir.  I don&#39;t want to clobber her stuff whenever I upload my site.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>