<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2003/12/02 on 80%</title>
    <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/12/02.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2003/12/02 on 80%</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2003-2015 Joe Beda CC by-nc-nd 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2003 13:03:11 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.eightypercent.net/archive/2003/12/02.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Avalon Visuals</title>
      <link>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00158.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2003 13:03:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.eightypercent.net/post/old/00158.html</guid>
      <description>

    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblogs.asp.net/dmarsh/&#34;&gt;Drew Marsh&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;posted an interesting
        article entitled &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://weblogs.asp.net/dmarsh/posts/40626.aspx&#34;&gt;Avalon
        Dissected&lt;/a&gt;.&#34;&amp;#160; It is great to see people taking an interest in Avalon at this
        level.&amp;#160; However, he got some of the details around Visuals wrong. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The graphics system in Avalon is new and is built to take advantage of the hardware.&amp;#160;
        Beyond this, there is a software engine for the cases when the hardware isn&#39;t supported.&amp;#160;
        On top of this, we&#39;ve built a &#34;scene graph&#34; system that natively supports animation
        and remoting.&amp;#160; In the normal case, the actual rendering of the scene graph is
        done on a dedicated composition thread where third party code isn&#39;t allowed to run.&amp;#160;
        The description of everything on screen and some primitive animation information is
        passed to this thread so that the rendering can happen independently of what is going
        on with the regular UI thread.&amp;#160; In the case when you are running an Avalon application
        from a remote machine (via Terminal Services or Remote Desktop) with an advanced client,
        this composition thread will run on the remote machine and the actual rendering of
        the scene graph will happen without any network traffic.&amp;#160; Some animations will
        be able to run on the remote machine without network traffic also.&amp;#160; 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        From the programming model point of view, a node in our scene graph is&amp;#160;called &lt;a href=&#34;http://longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/?//longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/lhsdk/ref/ns/msavalon.windows.media/c/visual/visual.aspx&#34;&gt;Visual&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;
        There are different types of visuals that are intended to be used for different purposes.&amp;#160;
        It is also important to note that UIElement derives from Visual so every UIElement &lt;em&gt;is-a&lt;/em&gt; Visual.&amp;#160;
        (At one point an Element &lt;em&gt;had-a&lt;/em&gt; visual but this was changed with the rearchitecture
        that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.simplegeek.com&#34;&gt;ChrisAn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.simplegeek.com/PermaLink.aspx/359c73aa-4711-4061-b9d9-16300d8d278e&#34;&gt;talks
        about&lt;/a&gt;.) 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Every Visual implements an interface called &lt;a href=&#34;http://longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/?//longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/lhsdk/ref/ns/msavalon.windows.media/i/ivisual/ivisual.aspx&#34;&gt;IVisual&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;
        There is no situation where a third user should be implementing IVisual.&amp;#160; The
        reason that we created this interface is so that we can use&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/default.asp?url=/library/en-us/csref/html/vcwlkExplicitInterfaceImplementationTutorial.asp&#34;&gt;explicit
        interface implementation&lt;/a&gt; to hide the methods on IVisual.&amp;#160; We didn&#39;t want
        to pollute the public object model for UIElement (and Button, etc.) with things that
        most users weren&#39;t going to be using. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        A Visual has the following capabilities: 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Children with a transform on each child 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Opacity 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Clip 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Content (defined differently for each visual type) 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Hit testing services 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Coordinate transformation services 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            Bounding box services 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            And in the future: blend mode and effect 
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        For each visual, the content of that visual is rendered followed by the children,
        from left to right.&amp;#160; The Z-order of any children are completely implied by their
        order in the visual tree.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Different specializations of Visual provide for specific types of content and for
        different flavors of public programming model.&amp;#160; Here are the main ones: 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;a href=&#34;http://longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/?//longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/lhsdk/ref/ns/msavalon.windows.media/c/containervisual/containervisual.aspx&#34;&gt;ContainerVisual&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;
            This Visual has all of its&amp;#160;capabilities reflected publically and has no intrinsic
            content. 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;a href=&#34;http://longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/?//longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/lhsdk/ref/ns/msavalon.windows.media/c/drawingvisual/drawingvisual.aspx&#34;&gt;DrawingVisual&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;
            This Visual also has all of its capabilties reflected publically.&amp;#160; Its content
            is 2D vector data that is stored with it.&amp;#160; You can think of it holding on to
            a &#34;metafile.&#34;&amp;#160; The way you change the content is&amp;#160;call&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/?//longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/lhsdk/ref/ns/msavalon.windows.media/c/drawingvisual/m/renderopen.aspx&#34;&gt;DrawingVisual.RenderOpen&lt;/a&gt;,
            get a DrawingContext and draw with that. 
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;a href=&#34;http://longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/?//longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/lhsdk/ref/ns/msavalon.windows.media/c/retainedvisual/retainedvisual.aspx&#34;&gt;RetainedVisual&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;
            This guy is special.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;He is meant to be derived from.&amp;#160; This is the
            Visual that UIElement derives from.&amp;#160; All of the services and properties are available
            either via private functions (RenderOpen) or via the IVisual interface only.&amp;#160;
            This visual can work in two modes: 
            &lt;ul&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;
                    Fully retained.&amp;#160; This is the default case.&amp;#160; In this case the visual is exacly
                    like&amp;#160;a DrawingVisual except the IVisual members are not reexposed in a public
                    way.&amp;#160; RenderOpen is also protected instead of private. 
                &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;
                    On&amp;#160;demand&amp;#160;retained.&amp;#160; If the&amp;#160;derived class implements &lt;a href=&#34;http://longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/?//longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/lhsdk/ref/ns/msavalon.windows.media/i/iretainedrender/iretainedrender.aspx&#34;&gt;IRetainedRender&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;and
                    sets the protected &lt;a href=&#34;http://longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/?//longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/lhsdk/ref/ns/msavalon.windows.media/c/retainedvisual/p/renderbounds.aspx&#34;&gt;RenderBounds&lt;/a&gt; property,
                    then &lt;a href=&#34;http://longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/?//longhorn.msdn.microsoft.com/lhsdk/ref/ns/msavalon.windows.media/i/iretainedrender/m/render.aspx&#34;&gt;IRetainedRender.Render&lt;/a&gt; will
                    be called back as necessary to fill in the &#34;metafile&#34; for this Visual.&amp;#160; They
                    system looks at the tree and decides, based on the RenderBounds, if this Visual is
                    on screen.&amp;#160; If it is, then the system calls IRetainedRender.Render and&amp;#160;the
                    derived class writes into the &#34;metafile&#34; via&amp;#160;a DrawingContext passed.&amp;#160; The
                    system then caches that metafile.&amp;#160; If the Visual is then pushed off screen for
                    some reason(scrolling, perhaps), then the system is free to throw away the cached
                    metafile to save space.&amp;#160; The user can force the system to throw away the metafile
                    by calling the protected RetainedVisual.InvalidateVisual call.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        When it comes time to render (scheduled via the Dispatcher class and coordinated with
        the animation system and layout) the system will walk the tree and decide what is
        and isn&#39;t on screen.&amp;#160; It will then call render on any RetainedVisuals as necessary
        and cache the result.&amp;#160; It also updates the data on the other thread for what
        is on screen so that the render can happen async from what is going on on the UI thread.&amp;#160;
        In this way, there is no &#34;render&#34; happening on the UI thread in the normal case.&amp;#160;
        Instead we are &#34;compiling&#34; the scene graph down to a simpler representation to run
        asynchronously on another thread or on another machine.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The bits that we shipped in the PDC don&#39;t have this system fully implemented.&amp;#160;
        For example, the composition thread isn&#39;t running completely async and we don&#39;t have
        rich TS support in.&amp;#160; Come beta, more of our system will be completed and up and
        working.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I&#39;m sure that this is confusing and that I&#39;ve missed some stuff, so feel free to ask
        questions and I&#39;ll do my best to answer.
    &lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>